Perls Galleries
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Exhibition, Loan, and Sales Records, 1937-1995, Series 4:; (Boxes 76-78; 2.1 linear feet)
  - Exhibition Records, 1937-1994, 4.1
    - Photographs, 30 Major Acquisitions, April 8 - May 17, 1975 (Box 76, Folder 33)
    - Photographs, Calder Exhibition, October 15 - November 15, 1975 (Box 76, Folder 34)
    - Photographs, Modern Masters, November 26, 1975 (Box 76, Folder 35)
    - Photographs, Fernand Léger - Major Oil Paintings, March 9 - April 17, 1976 (Box 76, Folder 36)
    - Photographs, Alexander Calder Works on Paper, October 12 - November 13, 1976 (Box 76, Folder 37)
    - Photographs, Darrel Austin, November 7 - December 2, 1976 (Box 76, Folder 38)
    - Photographs, 40 Years/40 Masterworks, October 18 - December 3, 1977 (Box 76, Folder 39)
    - Photographs, New Acquisitions, April 15 - June 27, 1980 (Box 76, Folder 40)
    - Photographs, Maillol, "La Montagne," June 1981 (Box 76, Folder 41)
    - Photographs, Picasso 100th Birthday Selection, October 27 - November 28, 1981 (Box 76, Folder 42)
    - Photographs, Group Exhibition, January 4 - March 20, 1982 (Box 76, Folder 43)
    - Photographs, Miró Gouache Paintings for Ubu Roi, March 23 - April 24, 1982 (Box 76, Folder 44)
    - Photographs, Major Acquisitions, 1982 (Box 76, Folder 45)
    - Photographs, Darrel Austin, September 21 - October 16, 1982 (Box 76, Folder 46)
    - Photographs, Major Acquisitions, October 19 - November 27, 1982 (Box 76, Folder 47)
    - Photographs, Group Exhibition, January 11 - February 15, 1983 (Box 76, Folder 48)
    - Photographs, Group Exhibition, April 5 - May 7, 1983 (Box 76, Folder 49)
    - Photographs, Group Exhibition, September 6 - October 15, 1983 (Box 76, Folder 50)
    - Photographs, Picasso and Peers, November 1 - December 22, 1983 (Box 76, Folder 51)
    - Photographs, Léger Exhibition, February-March 1984 (Box 76, Folder 52)
    - Photographs, Masterpieces of Pre-Columbian Art, April 11 - May 12, 1984 (Box 76, Folder 53)
    - Photographs, Pascin Exhibition, October 16 - November 42, 1984 (Box 76, Folder 54)
    - Photographs, Group Exhibition, November 27, 1984 - January 5, 1985 (Box 76, Folder 55)
    - Photographs, Three Sculptors: Archipenko, Calder, Maillol, May-June, 1985 (Box 76, Folder 56)
    - Photographs, Group Exhibition, September 16, 1985 - January 11, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 57)
    - Photographs, Group Exhibition, January 14 - April 22, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 58)
    - Photographs, Léger - Picasso, April 23 - September 5, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 59)
    - Photographs, Group Exhibition, October 28, 1986 - February 16, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 60)
    - Photographs, Raoul Dufy and the School of Paris, February 17 - March 31, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 61)
    - Photographs, Group Exhibition, April 14 - June 30, 1988 (Box 76, Folder 62)
    - Photographs, House (1016 Madison Avenue), undated (Box 76, Folder 63)
    - Photographs, Exhibitions at Other Galleries and Museums, November 15, 1966, undated (Box 76, Folder 64)
    - Press Releases, circa 1945, 1967-1991, undated (Box 76, Folder 65)
    - Publicity, 1937-1944 (Box 76, Folder 66)
  - Loan Records, 1964-1995, 4.2
    Loan records include documentation of loans to the Harmon-Meek Gallery, a notebook tracking loan requests received by the Perls Galleries, and a notebook tracking schedules of artwork loaned to other galleries for special exhibitions.
    - Harmon-Meek Gallery, 1981-1992 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Loan Requests Received, 1989-1995 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Paintings and Sculptures on Loan, 1964-1990 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Sales Records, 1937-1994, 4.3
    Sales records include artist inventories, one complete inventory list, invoices from 1941 through 1945, pick up and delivery receipts, an undated list of prices for artwork in the gallery's inventory, and index cards indicating the list price of artwork displayed in the gallery windows. Additional invoices can be found throughout Series 1: Correspondence.
    - Artist Inventories, Alexander Calder, 1944 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Artist Inventories, Aristide Maillol, 1988 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Artist Inventories, Jules Pascin, 1977, undated (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Inventory List, 1989-1993 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Invoices, January-June, 1941 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Invoices, July-December, 1941 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Invoices, January-June, 1942 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Invoices, July-December, 1942 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Invoices, January-April, 1943 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Invoices, May-August, 1943 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Invoices, September-December, 1943 (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Invoices, January-March, 1944 (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Invoices, April-July, 1944 (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Invoices, August-October, 1944 (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Invoices, November-December, 1944 (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - Invoices, January-February, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - Invoices, March-April, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 20)
    - Invoices, May-August, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 21)
    - Invoices, September-October, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 22)
    - Invoices, November-December, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 23)
    - Old Books of Photograph Numbers, circa 1937-197 (Box 77, Folder 24)
    - Pick Up and Delivery Receipts, 1972-1973 (Box 77, Folder 25)
    - Pick Up and Delivery Receipts, 1973-1974 (Box 77, Folder 26)
    - Pick Up and Delivery Receipts, 1974-1975 (Box 77, Folder 27)
    - Pick Up and Delivery Receipts, 1975-1976 (Box 77, Folder 28)
    - Pick Up and Delivery Receipts, 1975-1977 (Box 77, Folder 29)
    - Pick Up and Delivery Receipts, 1976-1977 (Box 77, Folder 30)
    - Pick Up and Delivery Receipts, 1977-1981 (Box 77, Folder 31)
    - Pick Up and Delivery Receipts, 1978-1980 (Box 77, Folder 32)
    - Pick Up and Delivery Receipts, 1980-1981 (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Pick Up and Delivery Receipts, 1981-1983 (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Pick Up and Delivery Receipts, 1983-1985 (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Pick Up and Delivery Receipts, 1984-1985 (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - Pick Up and Delivery Receipts, 1985-1987 (Box 77, Folder 37)
    - Pick Up and Delivery Receipts, 1990-1993 (Box 77, Folder 38)
    - Price Lists, undated (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Window Display Cards, 1954-1967 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Window Display Cards, 1967-1980 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Window Display Cards, 1980-1994 (Box 78, Folder 4)
- Clippings Files, 1943-1989, Series 5:; (Box 78; 0.5 linear feet)
  Clippings document artists represented by the gallery, exhibitions of gallery artists, and events in the art world. The clippings are arranged alphabetically by artist or by topic.
  - Archipenko, Alexander, 1962-1970 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Art Scene, 1962-1969 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Austin, Darrel, 1943-1950, 1961-1964, 1983 (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Bombois, Camille, 1967-1979 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Braques, Georges, 1964-1965 (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Chagall, Marc, 1964-1967 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Dalí, Salvador, 1970, 1979-1989 (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Derain, Andres, 1976 (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Dufy, Raoul, 1974 (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Gris, Juan, 1984 (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - Group: The Educated Eye, 1964 (Box 78, Folder 15)
  - Group: Major Acquisitions, 1962-1969 (Box 78, Folder 16)
  - Léger, Fernand, 1968-1969, 1976, 1984 (Box 78, Folder 17)
  - Maillol, Aristide, 1964, 1969-1979 (Box 78, Folder 18)
  - Miró, Joan, 1966, 1976-1979, 1982 (Box 78, Folder 19)
  - Modigliani, Amadeo, 1961-1966, 1971-1973, 1983-1985 (Box 78, Folder 20)
  - Pascin, Jules, 1962-1967, 1973-1979, 1984-1988 (Box 78, Folder 21)
  - Picasso, Pablo, 1962-1975, 1980, 1985 (Box 78, Folder 22)
  - Rouault, Georges, 1964 (Box 78, Folder 23)
  - Soutine, Chaim, 1968-1972, 1981-1982 (Box 78, Folder 24)
  - Utrillo, Maurice, 1974 (Box 78, Folder 25)
  - Vivin, Louis, 1967-1971 (Box 78, Folder 26)
  - Vlaminck, Maurice de, 1962, 1968, 1976-1977 (Box 78, Folder 27)
- Exhibition Catalogs, 1939-1980, Series 6:; (Boxes 78-79; 1.4 linear feet)
  The Perls Galleries' exhibition catalogs are incomplete but include catalogs from many of the gallery's exhibitions between 1939 and 1980, arranged chronologically.
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1939 (Box 78, Folder 28)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1940-1944 (Box 78, Folder 29)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1945 (Box 78, Folder 30)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1946-1947 (Box 78, Folder 31)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1948 (Box 78, Folder 32)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1949 (Box 78, Folder 33)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1949 (Box 78, Folder 34)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1950-1951 (Box 78, Folder 35)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1952 (Box 78, Folder 36)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1953 (Box 78, Folder 37)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1954 (Box 78, Folder 38)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1955 (Box 78, Folder 39)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1956 (Box 78, Folder 40)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1957 (Box 78, Folder 41)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1958 (Box 78, Folder 42)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1959 (Box 78, Folder 43)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1960 (Box 78, Folder 44)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1961 (Box 78, Folder 45)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1962 (Box 78, Folder 46)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1963-1964 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1965 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1966 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1967 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1968 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1969 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1970 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1971 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1972 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1974 (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1975 (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1977 (Box 79, Folder 13)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1978 (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1979 (Box 79, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1980 (Box 79, Folder 16)
- Drawings by John Canaday, circa 1967, 1972, Series 7:; (Box 80; 0.3 linear feet)
  This series includes eight original ink drawings and two pencil drawings from John Canaday's series entitled My Beautiful Girls, one of which is signed, and a folder of reproductions of eight drawings from the same series produced by the Archives of American Art.
  - My Best Girls: 8 Drawings by John Canaday, reproductions produced by the Archives of American Art, 1972 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Eight Loose Ink Drawings by John Canaday, 1967, undated (Box 80 (sol), Folder 2)
  - One Loose Pencil Drawing by John Canaday, undated (Box 80 (sol), Folder 3)
  - One Loose Pencil Drawing by John Canaday, undated (Box 80 (sol), Folder 4)